Noah T. Erickson

Electrical Engineer with 1+ years of experience working in engineering analysis for the automotive engineering industry and engineering design for the consumer goods industry. Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities, and possesses a wide range of technical skills. Enjoys being part of a team as well as managing, motivating and training a productive team, and thrives in high pressure and challenging working environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Blount International Portland, Oregon

Engineering Intern

June 2015 - Present

- Embedded systems design for the lawn and garden industry.
- Hardware layout and software development

Daimler Trucks North America

Portland, Oregon

Mechatronics Intern

March 2014 - September 2014

- Failure analysis of 12V systems on trucks.
- Worked closely with the 12V team to author component requirement specifications.

Papa Murphy's

Portland, Oregon

Lead Prep

March 2010 - June 2015

• Manage up to eight people, open and close the store, order product and manage inventory.

PROJECTS

Viking Motorsport's Digital Dashboard

Portland State University

 $ECE\ 412/413$ - $Senior\ Design$

Fall 2014 - Spring 2015

- A team of myself and four others designed a digital dashboard and integrated it on Portland State University's Viking Motorsport's electric vehicle.
- Skills learned: Embedded system design, communication protocols, time management, budget management, inter-team communication, rapid prototyping, various tools.

Motorcycle Proximity Sensor

Portland State University

ECE~411 - Industry~Design~Process

Fall 2014

- A team of myself and three others designed an embedded system that would alert motorcyclists of vehicles in their blind spots.
- Skills learned: Embedded system design, time management, budget management, design specifications, general design process.

EDUCATION

Portland State University

Portland, Oregon

BS Electrical Engineering

September 2013 - June 2016

- Upper division focus on analog design.
- Enrolled in MECOP.

PATENTS

• Python, C/C++, MATLAB, Embedded Systems Design, PCB Layout, Analog Circuit Design, Rapid Prototyping